export const questions = [
  {
    question: "Question 1",
    text: "Crummey provisions can be used in which of the following trusts?",
    options: ["A. Revocable", "B. 2503(c)", "C. Irrevocable", "D. 2503(b)"],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation:
      "A 2503(c) is IRS-approved to be a gift of a present interest. Answers A and D do not use Crummey provisions.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 2",
    text: `Ted is legally incompetent. He is incapable of making decisions. What type of documents can be drawn up by his
attorney to help take care of him and his assets?
I. A durable power of attorney
II. A living will
III. A revocable trust
IV. A durable power of attorney for health care`,
    options: [
      "A. All of the above",
      "B. I, IV",
      "C. II",
      "D. III",
      "E. None of the above",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 4,
    explanation:
      "To be valid, the documents must be executed prior to the principal's incapacity.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 3",
    text: `Tom Brown sets up an UTMA account for his son. Which of the following is true?`,
    options: [
      "A. This is a gift of a future interest.",
      "B. If Tom is the custodian dies while his son is a minor, then the custodial property will be included in Tom's gross estate.",
      "C. Income is taxable to Tom.",
      "D. Income can be used to satisfy any obligation to support his son.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    explanation:
      "This is a gift of a present interest. Income is taxable to his son (kiddie tax). The account income may not be used to satisfy any obligation to support for the minor.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 4",
    text: `Which of the following circumstances will cause life insurance to be included in the decedent's estate?
I. The insured sold his policy to someone else before he died.
II. The insured gifted his policy to his wife and she never changed the beneficiary (his estate) four years before he died.
III. The client gifted his spouse's policy to his daughter two weeks before he died.
IV. The insured owns his policy and dies.`,
    options: [
      "A. All of the above",
      "B. I, II, III, IV",
      "C. II, IV",
      "D. III, IV",
      "E. IV",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation:
      "Answers I and III are not included. Answer I is a viatical. Answer III he was not the insured.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 5",
    text: `Gifting stock in a S corporation should be considered in which of the following situations?`,
    options: [
      "A. The client's son will be going to a private high school to provide for tuition.",
      "B. The client's son will be going to a private expensive university to provide for tuition.",
      "C. The client's son has graduated early from college, and intends to start his own business.",
      "D. The client's son can't make up his mind whether or not to go on to college.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation:
      "Answer A and B will be subject to the kiddie tax. Answer D could be an answer if the son were more definite about what he was going to do if he didn't go to college. Answer C is the best choice.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 6",
    text: `What is another name for a bypass trust?
I. Non marital trust
II. "B" trust
III. Family trust
IV. Power of appointment trust`,
    options: [
      "A. All of the above",
      "B. I, II, III",
      "C. I, II, IV",
      "D. III, IV",
      "E. IV",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    explanation: "A power of appointment trust is a marital trust.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 7",
    text: "Which of the following about GSTT is true?",
    options: [
      "A. The $5.45 million is per grandchild.",
      "B. The annual exclusion is available for death.",
      "C. A skip person is a son or daughter of the transferor.",
      "D. A GSTT gift is also subject to gift tax.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    explanation:
      "A skip person is a beneficiary who is at least two generations younger than the transferor. The $5.45 is per grantor or person.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 8",
    text: `Jill and Bob live together in California, a community property state. They are concerned about one of them
dying because they have done no planning and they are not married. How should they hold their individual assets to
give them the greatest flexibility?`,
    options: [
      "A. As community property",
      "B. In joint tenancy with rights of survivorship (JTWROS)",
      "C. In a revocable trust",
      "D. In tenancy by the entirety",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation:
      "They are not married; therefore, community property and tenancy by the entirety will not work. JTWROS does not give them much flexibility to plan. Answer C is the best choice.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 9",
    text: `Which of the following is correct about a revocable living trust?`,
    options: [
      "A. It becomes irrevocable at the grantor's death.",
      "B. It cannot have multiple beneficiaries.",
      "C. The trustor and grantor cannot be the same person.",
      "D. It is irrevocable at inception.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    explanation:
      "The trustor and grantor are the same person. At death, a revocable living trust becomes irrevocable. These trusts can have multiple beneficiaries.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 10",
    text: `Which of the following are appropriate for gift splitting?
I. Irrevocable trusts for children
II. Custodial accounts for children
III. Revocable trusts for children
IV. Irrevocable life insurance trusts (ILIT)`,
    options: ["A. I, II", "B. II, III", "C. III, IV", "D. I, IV"],
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    explanation:
      "Answer I and IV are used where the owner wants to gift assets and/or income to family members.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 11",
    text: `Which type of trust does not provide for estate tax exclusion at death?`,
    options: [
      "A. A bypass trust",
      "B. A marital trust",
      "C. A QTIP trust",
      "D. A dynasty trust",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation: "The other two trusts pass tax free.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 12",
    text: `Which of the following would not qualify as a gift of a present interest?`,
    options: [
      "A. Gifts to a 2503(b) trust",
      "B. Gifts to a 2503(c) trust",
      "C. Gifts to an ILIT trust without Crummey provisions",
      "D. Gifts to a revocable trust",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation:
      "Answers A and B are definitely gifts of a future interest. A gift to a 2503(c) trust (a child's trust) is a gift of a present interest. A gift to an ILIT without Crummey provisions (spelled out) is a gift of a future interest.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 13",
    text: `Which of the following would not be classified as an exempt gift?`,
    options: [
      "A. A direct payment to a medical provider",
      "B. A direct payment for tuition",
      "C. A gift to a family member",
      "D. A gift to a charity",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation:
      "Gifts to family members can use the annual exclusion but are not classified as 'exempt gifts'. The others are called 'exempt gifts'.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 14",
    text: `Which of the following statements is true about terminal interests?`,
    options: [
      "A. If property passes to a spouse, it is always considered a terminal interest.",
      "B. Terminal interests are always subject to federal estate tax.",
      "C. Terminal interests always terminate upon the owner's death.",
      "D. The ILIT property is never a terminal interest.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    explanation:
      "If property passes to a spouse, it is not a terminal interest. A terminal interest is one that might terminate on the happening of some event or contingency or on the failure of some event or contingency. The ILIT property is never a terminal interest. It is an irrevocable gift or transfer. It is not a terminal interest.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 15",
    text: `Which of the following is not true about UGMA accounts?`,
    options: [
      "A. UGMA accounts are not separate legal entities.",
      "B. Income is taxable to the minor.",
      "C. UGMA accounts can include real estate.",
      "D. Custodial property is managed by the custodian until the minor comes of age.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation:
      "It is not a separate legal entity. Income is taxable to the minor.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 16",
    text: `Which of the following is an advantage of creating a family limited partnership?`,
    options: [
      "A. Allows for fractional discounts on property",
      "B. Allows for asset management within the family",
      "C. Protects assets from creditors",
      "D. All of the above",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    explanation: "Answers A, B, and D are advantages.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 17",
    text: `Which of the following assets is not subject to probate?`,
    options: [
      "A. Assets passing by will",
      "B. Joint tenancy assets",
      "C. Assets in a revocable living trust",
      "D. Life insurance proceeds with a named beneficiary",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation:
      "An asset passing by revocable trust is not subject to probate. Probate assets are subject to elective share, a will contest, or a family settlement agreement.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 18",
    text: "Which of the following is a terminal interest?",
    options: [
      "A. An irrevocable life insurance trust",
      "B. A marital trust",
      "C. A bypass trust",
      "D. A QTIP trust",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    explanation: "Please refer to the chart in Estate Workbook - Lesson 8.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 19",
    text: `Which of the following is correct about UTMA and UGMA?`,
    options: [
      "A. Only UTMA allows gifts at death - not UGMA.",
      "B. UGMA accounts can hold any type of asset.",
      "C. UTMA accounts are irrevocable and cannot be amended.",
      "D. UGMA accounts require a court order for modification.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    explanation: "Only UTMA allows gifts at death - not UGMA.",
  },
  {
    question: "Question 20",
    text: `When gifting from a jointly held checking account, how is the gift classified?`,
    options: [
      "A. One-half is considered to be made by each spouse.",
      "B. The gift is attributed solely to the person who wrote the check.",
      "C. It is a future interest and cannot be split.",
      "D. Gifts from jointly held accounts are not subject to tax.",
    ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    explanation:
      "A gift from a jointly held checking account is considered to be made one-half by each spouse.",
  },
];
